Guide to the Carl Feiss papers, [ca.1928]-1991
Feiss, Carl papers, [ca.1928]-1991
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Carl Feiss papers, [ca.1928]-1991
2635
Carl L. Feiss
64.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, published material, speeches, financial records, minutes, studies, job files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include family and business correspondence, reports, published material, speeches, financial records, minutes and studies, primarily concerning various consulting jobs (largely in the South). Also, material concerning Feiss' participation in various national and international commissions and committees and his work for regional commissions such as the Tennessee Valley Authority. Also, family and personal correspondence; and microfilm of Feiss' papers, 1946-1952, from the now defunct School of Architecture, University of Denver, Colorado.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Educator, city planner and historic preservation consultant.--He received his Bachelor of Architecture degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1931; a Master of City Planning from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1938; and studied at the Cranbrook Academy of Art under Eliel Saarinen from 1932-1935. Feiss taught at Columbia University School of Architecture from 1936 to 1941, where he became director of the Planning and Housing Division.
After serving as director for both the School of Architecture and the Department of Building Industry and Real Estate at the University of Denver from 1944 to 1950, he served on several planning commissions and boards of directors in Denver, as well as nationwide. Since 1971 he has worked in the University of Florida's Urban and Regional Planning Department. In addition to federal and municipal projects, he participated in the planning of the Denver Art Museum, the Baltimore Museum of Art, the University of Maryland, the University of North Carolina, the University of Denver and Cleveland College. He was also involved with the National Trust for Historic Preservation.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include family and business correspondence, reports, published material, speeches, financial records, minutes and studies, primarily concerning various consulting jobs (largely in the South). Also, material concerning Feiss' participation in various national and international commissions and committees, including the American Institute of Planners; the American Institute of Architects; the Union of International Architects; the Society of Architectural Historians; the National Trust for Historic Preservation; the Historic American Buildings Survey; and the International Conference on Monuments and Sites; and his work for regional commissions such as the Tennessee Valley Authority; the Missouri Valley Authority; the Connecticut Development Commission; Historic Savannah Foundation; Historic Annapolis; the Central Florida Regional Planning Council: the Louisville, Kentucky Historic Homes Foundation; the Tampa Bay Regional Planning Council; the Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments; and the Society for the Preservation of Landmarks in Western New York, Inc. Also, family and personal correspondence of Carl, Paul and Julian Feiss; correspondence of Sir Raymond Unwin; and microfilm of Feiss' papers, 1946-1952, from the now defunct School of Architecture, University of Denver, Denver, Colorado.
Job files include material concerning Anheuser-Busch, Inc.'s Busch Gardens; Tampa Bay Regional Planning Council's Rookery Bay Project; Naples and Collier City; East Central Florida project; Vieux Carré, New Orleans; and the Rye-Oyster Bay Bridge Project.
Also, oral history interviews with Charles B. Hosmer, Jr. and Kermit C. Parsons (RESTRICTED).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Feiss, Carl.; Feiss, Julian.; Feiss, Paul.; Unwin, Raymond, Sir, 1863-1940.; American Institute of Architects.; Anheuser-Busch, inc.--Busch Gardens Division.; American Institute of Planners.; Central Florida Regional Planning Council.; Connecticut Development Commission.; Historic American Buildings Survey.; Historic Annapolis.; International Conference on Monuments and Sites.; Historic Savannah Foundation.; National Trust for Historic Preservation in the United States.; Kentucky Historic Homes Foundation (Louisville, Ky.); Mid-Cumberland Council of Governments.; Missouri Valley Authority.; Society for the Preservation of Landmarks in Western New York.; Society of Architectural Historians.; Tampa Bay Regional Planning Council.; Tennessee Valley Authority.; Union of International Architects.; University of Denver.--Dept. of Building Industry and Real Estate.; University of Denver.--School of Architecture.; Rookery Bay Area Project.; Rye-Oyster Bay Bridge Project.
Subjects:
City planning--Connecticut.; City planning--Florida.; City planning--Missouri.; City planning--New York (State; City planning--Louisiana.; City planning--Louisiana--New Orleans.; Historic buildings--Conservation and restoration.; Historic sites--Conservation and restoration.; Schools of architecture.; City planning--Kentucky--Louisville.; Educators.; Architects.
Places:
Vieux Carré (New Orleans, La.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Oral Histories with Parsons and Hosmer (box 66) are restricted to approval of curator.
RELATED MATERIAL
Original papers from Carl Feiss' tenure at the University of Denver (ca.1946-1952), held by the University of Denver, Denver, Colorado, are available on microfilm.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Papers
A. Personal and Biographical Data
Boxes 1-2, 59, 63
1. Family Correspondence
2. Personal Material
3. Feiss's Calendars
4. Feiss's Daily Planners
B. General Correspondence
Boxes 3-6, 61-63
1. Named Correspondence
2. Chronological Correspondence
3. Alphabetical Correspondence
Series II. Professional Papers
A. Publications and Speeches
Boxes 6-10, 59
1. Books
2. Articles and Speeches
3. Reports
B. Conferences and Education Interests
Boxes 11-12, 64
C. Organizations
Boxes 12-21, 61-62
D. Projects
Boxes 21-36, 62-63, 66
E. Oversize Materials
Boxes 38-39
F. Reference Materials
Boxes 40-44, 52-58, 62-64
G. Oversize (Flat)
Boxes 49-51, 65, 67, Mapcase Folder 1-4
H. Edison Voicewriter Diamond Disks
Boxes 63
I. Audiocassettes
Boxes 64
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal Papers
  - Personal and Biographical Data
    - Photographs, biographical data, certificates, programs, first published drawings., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Documents relative to federal employment., 1949-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence., 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Photographs, 14+ color slides [daughters?], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Articles and speeches., 1936-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Housing in Denver., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Data on Denver including a letter from Walter Blucher., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Personal correspondence [examples of v-mail and censorship]., 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Personal correspondence., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence., 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Personal correspondence, Denver, vita, birth certificate., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Personal correspondence re: draft status., 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Documents re: draft status., 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 13-16)
    - Correspondence re: "Public Conversations on Music.", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Personal correspondence [mostly with father]., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - [duplicates? tossed] (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence., 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Mabian [high school yearbook], 1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Personal correspondence., 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Personal correspondence., 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Personal correspondence., 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Personal correspondence., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Personal correspondence [Mexico]., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Personal correspondence [Europe]., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Personal correspondence., 1937 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Personal correspondence., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Personal correspondence [first letter re: Columbia]., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Personal correspondence [at Cranbrook]., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Personal correspondence., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Personal correspondence., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Personal correspondence, clippings, photographs., 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Personal correspondence., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Personal correspondence., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Outgoing correspondence. [Drafts of reports are included.], 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
    - Outgoing correspondence. [Drafts of reports are included.], 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13-24)
    - Correspondence with the University of Florida., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Outgoing correspondence., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Outgoing correspondence., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28-33)
    - Outgoing correspondence., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 34-45)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and documents, A-Z., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 47-49)
    - Outgoing correspondence., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 50-61)
  - Feiss's Calendars
    - Calendars, 1992-1984 (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - Calendars, 1983-1978 (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Calendars, 1978-1976 (Box 59, Folder 31)
    - Calendars, 1976-1971 (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - Calendars, 1970-1969 (Box 59, Folder 33)
  - Feiss's Daily Planners
    - Daily Planners, 1935-1960 (Box 63, Folder 26)
    - Daily Planners, 1961-1969 (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Daily Planners [missing 1974-1975], 1970-1976 (Box 63, Folder 28)
    - Notebook, ca. 1936 (Box 63, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence
    - [not available] (Box 3)
    - General correspondence, April to December., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence, November to December., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General correspondence, A-Z., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
    - General correspondence., 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - General correspondence [Hitchcock]., 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - General correspondence [Podzemny]., 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - General correspondence., 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - General correspondence [Russell Van Nest Black, Hans Blumenfield, and a scenario for a movie on housing]., 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Taft, Charles K. "Planning in Goshen, New York:" correspondence and drawings., 1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - National Resources Planning Boards, Hampton Roads Regional Defense Council, Norfolk, Virginia., 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 13-16)
    - Personal correspondence., 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
    - Speaking invitations declined., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence with Sir James Jones., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Letter from Robert J. Lewis., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Invitation to 50th reunion of the University School, Cleveland., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Invitation to a book panel., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence with Senator Lawton Chiles., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence with Grady Clay., 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence with Walter Creese., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27a)
    - Correspondence with Robert H. Doyle., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence with George H. Dudley., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence wit Sir James Jones [see folder 22], 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence with Gordon Kennedy, Jr., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence with James W. Moody, Jr., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence with Richard Sharpe., 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence re: Stonorov bust of Catherine Bauer Wurster., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Office expenses., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Vitia of job applicants., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence re: rail transportation., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence with Charles Watle, Jr., Indiana., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence with Earle W. Newton, St. Augustine., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Invitation to Tocks Island Regional Advisory Council., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence with James H. Scheuer, Congressman from New York re: urban design and civic beauty. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth H. Wright, Montgomery, Ala., 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence with Edward J. Quirin., 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence with William E. McIntyre, Charlotte, North Carolina., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence with Virginia Outdoor Recreation Study Commission., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence with Rockville, Maryland., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence with Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence with J.W. Upson re: Woodbury, Connecticut., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence with William T. Colloredo., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence with Martin Meyerson re: "Rehabitilability.", 1955 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence with the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Milo B. Howard Jr. re: historic preservation in Alabama., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, including 701 grant to Huntsville, Alabama., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - American Assembly invitation., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: Appalachian Trail, Benton, MacKaye., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Associated Council of the Arts., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with The Research Group, Atlanta., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Carolina Cape Fear Corporation., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with William Bonnee, University of Arkansas., 1968-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Calvin Kytle., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Robert N. Anderson, Jr., 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with The Conservation Foundation., 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - [empty] (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence re Historic Galveston., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re: Conservation at Williamsburg and Georgia., 1967-1973 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence re: Interama in Florida., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence re: Interplan Corporation., 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Lake Michigan Planning Council, Planning Memo., 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Louisiana Regional Planning Council., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "A Two-Year Course in Geotechnics," Benton MacKaye., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence with Eugene W. Leake, Maryland Institute., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Reports on McLean Gardens, Washington Citizens for City Living., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence re: Interplan Corporation [see f18 above]., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence re: creating a historic preservation district in New Orleans., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Letters re: fees., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence re: planning contest in Perugia, Italy., 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence re: Princeton Conference., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence with S. Douglas Fleet, Richmond, Virginia., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence with Royal Society for Promotion of Health., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence re: Salzburg Seminar in American Studies., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence re: House of Representatives bill on Environmental Quality., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence with Robert Stipe, Chapel Hill, North Carolina., 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence re: consultancy in Kentucky., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence re: Virginia Historical Landmarks., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Letter to Walter Muir Whitehill re: Arthur Dow, autobiographical., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, A-R., 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 37-55)
    - Correspondence, S-Z., 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence, A-Z., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8-27)
- Series II. Professional Papers
  - Publications and Speeches
    - Copy for chapter in Open Space Book, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Citizen?s Guide for Historic Conservation., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 29-32)
    - Letter re: publication of Urban Problems and Techniques 2., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Chapter on Washington for the book, World Capitals., 1970 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Chapter in The New City., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - "The History of Planned New Towns in the United States.", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Reference in The Courant Magazine, September 21, 1969, to Feiss having written the Introduction to Portrait of Essex by Marie Moore. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - "With Heritage So Rich," documents and correspondence of Special Committee on Historic Preservation., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 38-42)
    - Correspondence with Frederic R. Stevenson, much re: publication of Our Heritage of Planned Communities., 1945-1956 (Box 6, Folder 43-44)
    - "Colorado State Planning and Zoning Acts.", 1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Denver Municipal Year Book.", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "The Planned Community: A North American Heritage," with Frederick Stevenson; drafts, photographs, maps, research resources, correspondence., 1939-1944 (Box 7, Folder 3-21)
    - "America?s Proudest Architectural Achievements of the Past 200 Years," AIA Journal, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - [The World Future Society], 1975 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - [Article for The Louisville Times], 1973 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "The Training and Planning and Zoning Officials," draft of speech., 1972 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "What do We do Next for Florida?" draft; The News and Courier, Charleston, South Carolina, report of a speech by Feiss., 1972 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "It's What's Inside That Counts," Preservation News., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Establishment of a National Land Use Policy" and related materials., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "Regional Planning" and related materials., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Review," Aspen/Dreams and Dilemmas in Historic Perservation, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Random Meditation of the Inderdisciplinary Man in the Modern World.", 1971 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - "The Demise of the Grand Rapids City Hall," The Law in Preservation Issues., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Summary of remarks on the National Trust for Historic Preservation at the Second Annual Indiana Conference on Historic Preservation., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - "Art and Wasteland," Art and Education., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - "The Architect, the Environment and the World," speech for UIA Town Planning Commission., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - "The Urban Growth and New Community Development Act of 1970." (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - "Testimony on S.3354, National Land Use Policy before the Senate Interior and Isular Affairs Committee., 1970 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - "An Agenda for Action.", 1969 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - "Build Utopia Now," unpublished article with correspondence., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - "The Role of the State in Environmental Design." Environmental Design Legislation for States., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - "Carl Feiss in Conversation with Professor Arthur Ling," Journal of the Town Planning Institute., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - "The Heritage of the Past in the City of Tomorrow," UIA Review of the International Union of Architects., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - People and Planning. Report of the Committee on Public Participation in Planning, Ministry of Housing and Local Government. Feiss is listed as a person who gave assistance to Skeffington Committee, but there is no indication of what his contribution was., 1969 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - "True or False: Living Architecture, Old and New," Historic Preservation., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Testimony on Urban Highways before the Senate Committee on Public Works, Subcommittee on Roads, with correspondence and clippings., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - "Taking Stock: A Resume of Planning Accomplishments in the United States," Environment and Change: The Next Fifty Years., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - AIP Newsletter. Report on the 50th Anniversary program with a picture of Feiss., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Town and Country Planning., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - "USA: New Communities?or Their Simulacrum," Town and Country Planning., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - "Survey, Evaluation and Registration," Historic Preservation Tomorrow., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Speech, Connecticut Society of Architects., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - "Outer Skins and Contact Environments," AIA Journal. Also text for speech on the same subject., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - "Red Light, Green Light," Symposium on Urban Development, McMasters University., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - "Let's Pick Up Some Bricks and Make Music," Virginia Bearing Wall Conference., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - "New Towns?An American Tradition," American Builder Magazine., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "The Responsibility of State Government for Good Urban Design," Commission to Study the Necessity and Feasibility of Metropolitan Government; report, drafts and correspondence., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Book review for AIA Journal, August 1965. Reps, The Making of Urban America. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "The Architecture of Civilization," address to AIA Convention, Washington, D.C., June 17, 1965. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Urban Waters," address to White House Conference on Natural Beauty, May 24, 1965. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Book review for AIA Journal, May 1965. Appleyard, Lynch and Myer, The View From the Road. And reply by authors. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Book review for The National Trust, May/June 1965. Reps, The Making of Urban America. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Agenda for Fifty Years," address to Pacific Southwest Council American Society of Civil Engineers, April 20, 1965. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Planning the Well-Designed City," The First Annual Peter B. Andrews Memorial Lecture, Syracuse University, March 11, 1965. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Progress and Poverty," article in Law and Contemporary Problems: Urban Problems and Prospects, Winter 1965. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Copy for chapter in Open Space Book, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Book review. Chermayeff and Alexander, Community and Privacy., 1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "Planning Theory and Practice in the United States," for Mr. L. Virgili, November 12, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "Coordination with Community Master Plans: The Eight R's of Modernization," address to Building Research Institute 1964 Fall Conference: "Modernization of Buildings." (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Book review. Lubove, The Progressives and the Slums., 1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Book review for AIA Journal, November 1964. Osborn and Whittick, The New Towns: The Answer to Megalopolis. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Little View into a Big World," article in AIP Journal, June 9, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "An Introduction to the Preservation of Historic Areas in the United States of America," a paper for the International Federation for Housing and Planning Standing Committee of "Historic Urban Areas," Venice, May 22-24, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "The City as a Vehicle of Faith," article in The Washington Seminar, March 2-3, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "The Design of the Second United States," keynote address for 33rd Annual Meeting of the National Housing Conference, Washington, D.C., February 23-25, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "The Voice of the City," address to The Friends of the University Library, The University of Miami, January 31, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 19)